A Guide to the Virginia Canals and Navigations Society Records, 1966-2009
Library of Virginia
- R.G. 3-4 - VCNS Projects - Byrd Park Pump House. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- R.G. 3-5 - VCNS Projects - Tidewater Lock Stones. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- R.G. 3-6 - VCNS Projects - Bibliography of Virginia Canals. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- R.G. 3-7 - VCNS Projects - History of VCNS. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- R.G. 3-8 - VCNS Projects - James River Film. (Box 19, Folder 9-14)
- R.G. 3-9 - VCNS Projects - Ben Salem Lock Model Exhibit. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- R.G. 3-10 - VCNS Projects - "From Canal to Constitution" Essay Contest, 1987. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- R.G. 3-11 - VCNS Projects - Adopt-a-Lock. (Box 20, Folder 3)
- R.G. 3-12 - VCNS Projects - Dismal Swamp Canal Superintendent's/Toll House Restoration. (Box 20, Folder 4)
- R.G. 3-13 - VCNS Projects - Goochland County, James River and Kanawha Canal Exhibit. (Box 20, Folder 5)
- R.G. 3-14 - VCNS Projects - VCNS Web Page. (Box 20, Folder 6)
- R.G. 3-15 - VCNS Projects - Richmond Riverfront Development. (Box 20, Folder 7)
- R.G. 3-16 - VCNS Projects - Appomattox Riverwalk. (Box 20, Folder 8)
- R.G. 3-17 - VCNS Projects - Virginia Museum of Trasportation Canal Exhibit. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- R.G. 3-18 - VCNS Projects - Alexandria Tidelock Historical Marker. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- R.G. 3-19A - VCNS Projects - VCNS Institutional Home - The Library of Virginia. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- R.G. 3-19B - VCNS Projects - VCNS Institutional Home - Lynchburg College. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- R.G. 3-20 - VCNS Projects - "Tiller" Binder Sales. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- R.G. 3-21 - VCNS Projects - River Mileage System. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- R.G. 3-22 - VCNS Projects - "George Washington's Canal at Great Falls, Virginia" by Tom Hahn. (Box 21, Folder 3)
- R.G. 3-23- VCNS Projects - Publication Outreach. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- R.G. 3-24 - VCNS Projects - Merger of VCNS and JRBF. (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
- R.G. 3-25 - VCNS Projects - Great Bridge Lock Medallion. (Box 21, Folder 7)
- R.G. 4-1 - Virginia Waterways Register - Status of Virginia Canals. (Box 21, Folder 8)
- R.G. 4-2 - Virginia Waterways Register - Virginia Canals Structures Inventory. (Box 21, Folder 9)
- R.G. 4-3-1 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Patowmack Canal. (Box 21, Folder 10)
- R.G. 4-3-2 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Goose Creek Locks. (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
- R.G. 4-3-3 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Gilmerton Lock (Dismal Swamp). (Box 21, Folder 13)
- R.G. 4-3-4 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Varney's Falls Dam. (Box 21, Folder 14)
- R.G. 4-3-5 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Palmyra Ruins. (Box 21, Folder 15)
- R.G. 4-3-6 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Union Mills Canal Outlet Locks. (Box 21, Folder 16)
- R.G. 4-3-7 - Virginia Waterways Register - National Historic Register Nominations - Rivanna Navigation. (Box 21, Folder 17)
- R.G. 4-6 - Corps of Engineers Drawing, James River and Kanawha Canal, Charles Ellet, Jr., Chief Engineer. (Box 22, Folder 1)
- R.G. 5-1 - Other Source Info - Canal Organizations in U.S. and Canada. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- R.G. 5-2 - Other Source Info - George Washington Papers, Minnesota Historical Society. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- R.G. 5-3 - Other Source Info - Thomas F. Hahn Book Collection, Lyceum Museum, Alexandria. (Box 22, Folder 4)
- R.G. 5-4 - Other Source Info - Bibliography: "The Patowmack Canal," National Geographic Society. (Box 22, Folder 5)
- R.G. 5-5 - Other Source Info - Biblography: Mariner's Museum, Newport News. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- R.G. 5-6 - Other Source Info - "Canal Boat Construction Index," ACS. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- R.G. 5-7 - Other Source Info - Bibliography: "Backsights," VDOT. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- R.G. 5-8 - Other Source Info - Bibliography: The Library of Virginia. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- R.G. 5-9 - Other Source Info - James River and Kanawha Canal Library Collections Shelf List. (Box 22, Folder 10)
- R.G. 5-10 - Other Source Info - Reynolds Canal Center. (Box 22, Folder 11-13)
- R.G. 5-11 - Other Source Info - Haxall, Theodore, Canal Boat Records Index, Valentine Museum, Richmond. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- R.G. 5-12 - Other Source Info - Virginia State Library Canal Exhibit, January-March, 1994. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- R.G. 5-13 - Other Source Info - Canal Information, Special Collections, Duke University. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- R.G. 5-14 - Other Source Info - PASCL Photograph Directory, Temple University. (Box 22-23)
- R.G. 5-15 - Other Source Info - "The Virginia Genealogist" - Various Canal References. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- R.G. 5-16 - Other Source Info - "A Guide to Canal Records in the New York State Archives". (Box 23, Folder 2)
- R.G. 6-1 - "Thomas Harbaugh's Journal" (C & O). (Box 23, Folder 3)
- R.G. 6-2 - "The Rappahannock Canal" by Donald S. Callaham. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- R.G. 6-3 - "Patowmack Canal Preservation Alternatives" - National Park Service. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- R.G. 6-4 - "The James River Batteau: Tobacco Transport in Virginia" by Bruce G. Terrell. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- R.G. 6-5 - Batteau Construction Notes. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- R.G. 6-6 - "1823 Survey of the River Potomac". (Box 23, Folder 8)
- R.G. 6-7 - "1785 Compact and Boundary Between Virginia and Maryland". (Box 23, Folder 9)
- R.G. 6-8 - "Reminders of Commerce on Potomac River" by Osgood R. Smith. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- R.G. 6-9 - "Lynchburg and its People" by W. Asbury Christian. (Box 23, Folder 11)
- R.G. 6-10 - "Richmond and Alleghany Railroad Water Rents Ledger, 1882". (Box 23, Folder 12)
- R.G. 6-11 - "The Checkered Career of Tobias Lear" by Ray Brighton. (Box 23, Folder 13)
- R.G. 6-12 - "The Transfer of Early Industrial Technologies to America". (Box 23, Folder 14)
- R.G. 6-13 - "History of Allegany County, Maryland". (Box 23, Folder 15)
- R.G. 6-14 - "The Unseen River" by Garvey Winegar. (Box 23, Folder 16)
- R.G. 6-15 - "Coton" - Home of Thomas Ludwell Lee, 1803, Goose Creek, Virginia. (Box 23, Folder 17)
- R.G. 6-16 - 1807 Acts Passed by the Virginia General Assembly - Proposed Meherrin River Canal. (Box 23, Folder 18)
- R.G. 6-17 - "Backsights" by Howard Newlon, VDOT. (Box 23, Folder 19)
- R.G. 6-18 - Wooling Family Papers. (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- R.G. 6-19 - Rappahannock Canal System, 1988. (Box 24, Folder 3)
- R.G. 6-20 - "The Fate of Washington's Bequest to a National University" Essay. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- R.G. 6-21 - "Economic History of the James River and Kanawha Canal" by Homer Marshall, Jr. (Box 24, Folder 5)
- R.G. 6-22 - "North River Navigation Company" by Douglas E. Brady. (Box 24, Folder 6)
- R.G. 6-23 - "Journey on the James". (Box 24, Folder 7)
- R.G. 6-24 - Woolen Mills Dam, Charlottesville. (Box 24, Folder 8)
- R.G. 7 - VCNS Photograph Collection. (Box 24, Folder 9)
- R.G. 8-1 - Canal Societies Periodicals - American Canal Society - "American Canals". (Box 24, Folder 10-13)
- R.G. 8-2 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Illinois Canal Society Newsletter. (Box 25, Folder 1)
- R.G. 8-3 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of Indiana - "Indiana Canals". (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
- R.G. 8-4 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of Indiana Newsletter. (Box 25, Folder 4-6)
- R.G. 8-5 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Middlesex (Mass.) Canal Association - "Towpath Topics". (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
- R.G. 8-6 - Canal Societies Periodicals - C & O Canal Association - "Along the Towpath". (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
- R.G. 8-7 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Calvert Marine Museum - "Bugeye Times". (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
- R.G. 8-8 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of New Jersey - "On the Level". (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
- R.G. 8-9 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of New York State - "Bottoming Out". (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
- R.G. 8-10 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Museum Associates - "Canal Packet". (Box 26, Folder 11)
- R.G. 8-11 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Neversink Valley Area Museum - "The Towpath". (Box 26, Folder 12)
- R.G. 8-12 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of Ohio - "Towpaths". (Box 27, Folder 1-4)
- R.G. 8-13 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Canal Society of Ohio Newsletter. (Box 27, Folder 5)
- R.G. 8-14 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Pennsylvania Canal Society - "Canal Currents". (Box 27, Folder 6)
- R.G. 8-15 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Hugh Moore Historical Park and Museums (PA) - "The Locktender". (Box 27, Folder 7)
- R.G. 8-16 - Canal Societies Periodicals - James River Batteau Festival - "Virginia Batteau Journal". (Box 27, Folder 8)
- R.G. 8-17 - Canal Societies Periodicals - James River Batteau Festival - "Quarterly Review". (Box 27, Folder 9)
- R.G. 8-18 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Great Falls Park (National Park Service) - "Sharper". (Box 27, Folder 10)
- R.G. 8-19 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Savannah-Ogeechee Canal Society (GA) Newsletter. (Box 27, Folder 11)
- R.G. 8-20 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Rideau Canal (Canada) - "Steam and Stone". (Box 27, Folder 12-13)
- R.G. 8-20 - Canal Societies Periodicals - Rideau Canal (Canada) - "Steam and Stone". (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
- R.G. 9-0 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Alexandria Canal. (Box 28, Folder 5)
- R.G. 9-1 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Appomattox River. (Box 28, Folder 6)
- R.G. 9-2 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Albemarle and Chesapeake Canal. (Box 28, Folder 7)
- R.G. 9-3 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Dismal Swamp Canal. (Box 28, Folder 8-10)
- R.G. 9-4 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Goose Creek. (Box 28, Folder 11)
- R.G. 9-5 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - James River. (Box 28, Folder 12-13)
- R.G. 9-6 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Maury (North) River. (Box 29, Folder 1)
- R.G. 9-7 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Potomac River. (Box 29, Folder 2)
- R.G. 9-8 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Potowmack Canal. (Box 29, Folder 3)
- R.G. 9-9 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Rappahannock River. (Box 29, Folder 4)
- R.G. 9-10 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Rivanna River. (Box 29, Folder 5)
- R.G. 9-11 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Shenandoah River. (Box 29, Folder 6)
- R.G. 9-12 - Virginia Canals and Rivers - Slate and Willis's Rivers. (Box 29, Folder 7)
- R.G. 10-0 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - "Canals and Railroads of the Mid-Atlantic States, 1800-1860" by Christopher T. Baer. (Box 29, Folder 8)
- R.G. 10-1 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - American Canal Guide. (Box 29)
- R.G. 10-3 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Indiana Canals. (Box 29, Folder 9)
- R.G. 10-4 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Maryland Canals. (Box 29, Folder 10)
- R.G. 10-5 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Maine Canals. (Box 29, Folder 11)
- R.G. 10-7 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - New Jersey Canals. (Box 29, Folder 12)
- R.G. 10-8 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - New York Canals. (Box 29, Folder 13)
- R.G. 10-9 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Ohio Canals. (Box 30, Folder 1)
- R.G. 10-10 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Pennsylvania Canals. (Box 30, Folder 2)
- R.G. 10-19 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Belgian Canals. (Box 30, Folder 3)
- R.G. 10-20 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Canadian Canals. (Box 30, Folder 4)
- R.G. 10-20A - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Rideau Canal. (Box 30, Folder 5)
- R.G. 10-20B - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Welland Canal. (Box 30, Folder 6)
- R.G. 10-22 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - English Canals. (Box 30, Folder 7)
- R.G. 10-25 - U.S. and Foreign Canals - Panama Canal. (Box 30, Folder 8)
- R.G. 11 - Models/Dioramas Collection. (Box 30, Folder 9)
- R.G. 11-1 - Model - Tugboat, T. Haxall. (Box 30, Folder 10)
- R.G. 11-2 - Model - Schooner "America," T. Haxall. (Box 30, Folder 11)
- R.G. 11-3 - Diorama - Scottville Basin. (Box 30, Folder 12)
- R.G. 11-4 - Model - Indiantown Creek Aquaduct, Appomattox Canal. (Box 30, Folder 13)
- R.G. 11-5 - Lock Demonstration Model (Watered). (Box 30, Folder 14)
- R.G. 11-6 - Buena Vista Aquaduct Model. (Box 30, Folder 15)
- R.G. 11-9 - Diorama - Byrd Creek Aquaduct/Culvert. (Box 30, Folder 16)
- R.G. 11-10 - Diorama - Cedar Point Lock Keepers House and Lock #7, James River and Kanawha Canal. (Box 30, Folder 17)
- R.G. 12 - Archaelogical Artifacts. (Box 30, Folder 18)
- R.G. 12-1 - Richmond Basin Artifacts Display. (Box 30, Folder 19)
- R.G. 12-2 - Batteau Artifacts Display (Jim Seay). (Box 30, Folder 20)
- R.G. 12-5 - Pig Iron "Liberty Furnace". (Box 30, Folder 21)
- R.G. 12-7 - Skip Pan Tool. (Box 30, Folder 22)
- R.G. 13 - Artworks Collection. (Box 30, Folder 23)
- R.G. 13-1 - Print - "Richmond at Dawn". (Box 30, Folder 24)
- R.G. 13-6 - Music - "The Canaller's Songbook". (Box 30, Folder 25)
- R.G. 13-7 - Music - "Minstrel Show". (Box 30, Folder 26)
- R.G. 13-12 - Print - "Richmond Packet Office". (Box 30, Folder 27)
- R.G. 13-14 - Lyrics. (Box 30, Folder 28)
- R.G. 14 - Map Collection. (Box 30, Folder 29)
- R.G. 14-11 - Coast and Geodetic Survey Maps, James River (3 sheets), 1911. (Map-case 2, Drawer 12)
- R.G. 15-1 - Newspaper Clippings - Virginia Canals/Navigations. (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
- R.G. 15-1 - Newspaper Clippings - Virginia Canals/Navigations (Not Sorted). (Box 31, Folder 4-6)
- R.G. 15-2 - Newspaper Clippings - Batteaux. (Box 31, Folder 7-8)
- R.G. 15-3 - Newspaper Clippings - Other Canals. (Box 31, Folder 9)
- R.G. 16 - Video Collection. (Box 31, Folder 10)
- R.G. 17 - Ephemera Collection. (Box 31, Folder 11)
- R.G. 17-1 - VCNS Cloth Patch. (Box 31, Folder 12)
- R.G. 17-7 - James River and Kanawha Canal Company Stock Certificate, 1861. (Box 31, Folder 13)
- R.G. 17-8 - Copy of Stock Certificate - James River Canal Packet Company. (Box 31, Folder 14)
- R.G. 17-9 - Copy of Virginia State Navigation Lottery Ticket, 1827. (Box 31, Folder 15)
- R.G. 18-2 - VCNS Research Library. (Box 31, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Publications. (Box 32)
- Accessions Card File, James River and Kanawha Company Library Card Catalog, Slides (George Washington Potomac Canal, 1982-1983), Cassette Tapes of National Park Service and VCNS Meeting, 1985. (Box 33)